This is Unit 1 of Pimsler's Speak and Read Essential French 3.
Listen to this conversation, which takes place at a dinner party in Nice.
Enchante, Monsieur Celier, Je Mapel Julia Johnson.
Vousette American Madame Johnson.
We Je New York.
Vouconis New York?
El Fousetrefoi.
Vousa Vais en Jonvier fetrefoi New York.
Evous New York.
Do you remember how to say, here is a photo?
Voila in futu.
You're with an acquaintance, he says.
I have a few photos.
Did Le Calque Fout Calque Fout A few photos of my trip to New York Calque Fout de Mont Voyage New York Calque Fout de Mont Voyage, New York De Mont de Lui Court Letalia, New York Contest New York Coin Vousitalier New York Il Repont in January Angelvieu De Mondelou, how is the weather?
Quelton Esquil Fauze Quelton Fauzette Say, it was bad, referring to the weather I fauze mauve Mauve It was really bad I fause Vremont Mauve Ildi We had snow and also some rain.
Say Honou Honaud Lanage Eusila Pleu Honaud Lanege Eusie la Pleu How is the weather down there in the summer?
Quelton squilfe la barnette Quelton fetil la barnet Dit.
In summer it's very hot Onete il fetrecha Il fait on et il faitrechau Comonditille In Nice it is never very cold Anice ille fégametre foijametremetre foi and it's often very hot De Mondelu Contil Vaurtourne Contesque visa retourney vou tourne la ba Command your next trip Votre procha voyage Votre procha voyage When are you going to take your next trip to New York Contesseque vous fair vaunt voyage New York vaunt voyage in New York I repent next month Le moi pocha Le moi pocha I'm going there next month watch the word order Givet de moi pocha Le moi pocha Givet de moi pocha Dit then have a good tripon voyage Now suppose you're with another acquaintance Como d'Iton for lunch Adejeunais Adejeunais Comon votramis d'Tille.
I'd like to invite you for lunch Je mre bous invitaire degenais Je mre bous invitaire degener tomorrow at one o'clock De Maison at the restaurant Le Gourmet Au restaurant le gourmet Dit with pleasure Ave pleasire at one o'clock it's fine Auneur ce trebion Auneur ce trebion He wants to show you where the restaurant is como detile here's a map on the map Jour le plan Jour le plan I can Je pu I can show you on the map Je peu vous montre sur le plan I can show you on the map where the restaurant is.
Be careful of the word order.
Je peu vous montre sur le plant oui le restaurant Je peuvoumontre sur le plan, oui le restaurant.
Yes, show me, please.
Show me the way to go to the restaurant, le chumin.
Montremont le chemin pour a lau restaurant.
Le chemin pour a lau restaurant Montremois le chemin pour a leu restaurant.
Comonditon.
To arrive late.
Arrivient rotar.
I would not like to arrive late.
Je namre pa rivon rotar Je nèmre pas a rivon rotar showing you on the map, he says, Look, the restaurant is down there.
Thank you.
Until tomorrow at one o'clock.
Merci, ad de ma honor.
Now, suppose you're at a cocktail party in France.
You introduce yourself to someone standing next to you.
How do you say, My name is Je Matel De Mondi?
And you, what is your name?
Et vous, come on vous a plevous Comon vous a plevous Someone else comes over and introduces himself.
Ecouti.
Permit moi de presente.
Marc duval.
Here's how to say, introduce.
Ecouti, repetiti.
Presente.
Now say, permit me, or allow me.
Permit moi.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Répetit.
Permit moi de ma presenté.
Presente.
Meu presente.
De mau presente.
Permit moi de mau presente.
Which word means myself.
Allow me to introduce myself.
Permit moire me presente.
Permit moi me presente.
Dit.
Pleased to meet you.
Enchante.
Enchante de fervat reconnaissance.
You may use either the short or the long way to say, pleased to meet you.
Now say, allow me to introduce myself.
Permit me de me presente.
Suppose your name is Susan Peters.
Tell him your name.
Jevapelle Susan Peters.
Jean-Pelle.
Here's how to ask someone where he's from.
Repetitive.
Do it vous Dou et vous Como de Monde vous.
From where Du Now ask Mr.
Duval, where are you from?
Do it vous, Monsieur Duval.
Comment repentile.
I am from Nice, and you Je suit Denise, et vous Denise Je suis Denise, Et vous Did.
I am American.
Say first male and then female.
Je suis America Je suis American Tell him you live in Washington with your family.
Jebita Washington avic my family E command vous.
Allow me to introduce myself Permit Moire de Ma presente.
Monsieur Duval Répon.
Pleased to meet you.
You say you live in Washington.
Did you grow up in Washington?
Repeat ceased.
Escape vousit Levier, Washington Elové Et Elovais Avais Elovais Vousa vaisé vousa vais et et love vous a vaisette levé Washington vous avait elvie literally means you were brought up.
Commanded vous.
I grew up Jai T.
Jai Telvie Martin, Esse de Mondi.
Where did you grow up?
Comment, Monsieur Duval de Montille.
Did you grow up in Washington?
Escape us a vaisette elvia, Washington Usa vaisélve, Washington Ariponi.
No, not in Washington.
No, Paza, Washington, Paza, Washington Command Vous.
I grew up in Los Angeles.
Los Angeles Jai Telvie, Los Angeles.
But now I live in Washington.
Mais ma ten jabita, Washington I have been living there.
You say, I there live Giabit Giabit Dit.
I have been living there since two years.
Giabit de Pidozon Giabit de Pidozon.
Susan Peters wants to tell Mr.
Duval that her husband is a teacher.
Ecouti repetit.
Mon marie et professeur professor mon marie et professeur professeur refers to a teacher beyond the elementary level.
Command d'itel.
My husband is a teacher.
Mon marie et professor Esse du Dieu.
He grew up Ilait Ilait Elvie He grew up in Washington.
Ilaites Elvira, Washington Elovie, Ilaites Elvira, Washington Command, allow me to introduce myself.
Permit mode deme presente Command d'In pleased to meet you Enchante Enchante de Ferre Connaissance Monsieur Duval de Mard.
You say your husband is a teacher Voudique que votre marie, professor Voudique votre marie professor And what is your profession?
Repeat E que vot profession La profession Votre profession Quale votre profession Dit your profession Votre profession What is your profession profession Répundi?
I work Jotravaille I work in bank Jotravais d'Orsun Bonc Dorsun Bonc And your husband Evotre Marie He's a teacher Il Professor Did yes he's a teacher He grew up in Washington Ila et Ilvier, Washington But me, I grew up in Los Angeles Maisoi J Ilvier Los Angeles J Ilvie Memoir J'Étilvier, Los Angeles.
Monsieur Juval de Monde, what is your profession?
Questre profession.
Do you work in a bank?
Yes, I work at a French bank in Washington.
Ah, misery.
Now suppose your name is Diane Jackson, and you're at a reception in Nice.
How would you say to the person standing beside you?
Allow me to introduce myself.
Permit mode presenté.
My name is Diane Jackson.
Je Mapel Dienne Jackson.
Now listen to his response.
Enchante, Madame Jackson.
Je Perget.
Henri Berget.
Say, pleased to meet you, Mr.
Berget.
Enchante, Monsieur G.
Enchante favourable reconnaissance, Monsieur Bergerget.
Now ask him where he is from.
Doued vous Douaisvous, Monsieur Berget paris vous.
Tell him you're from Boston.
Je s de Boston say, but I grew up in New York.
Maiser till New York ask him what his profession is.
Questre profession Je s professor, et vous.
Tell him you work in a bank in Boston.
Je travel nonsun banqua Boston Esque vous menisuin france.
Say, yes, I come often to France in France say, and I know France well enough.
La France Et je conné la france bien je conné la france bien.
I travel a lot in France.
Je bouque vouje en France.
This is the end of today's lesson.
When you continue the next unit tomorrow, please begin with truck number two.